<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyDelhi Blog</title><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/feeds/anubhav-bhambri.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pydelhi.org/blog/</id><updated>2018-03-31T00:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>PyDelhi Meetup at Connaught Place</title><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/pydelhi-meetup-31-march-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-31T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-31T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anubhav Bhambri</name></author><id>tag:pydelhi.org,2018-03-31:blog/pydelhi-meetup-31-march-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="PyDelhi Meetup" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/pydelhi-31-03-18-1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time the meetup was at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Srijan"&gt;Srijan Technologies&lt;/a&gt;, Connaught Place, Delhi. And everybody was already half way through the introduction session when I reached (yeah, I was late). Everybody introduced themselves and we straight away jumped into the talks without any further ado.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rajataaron"&gt;Rajat&lt;/a&gt; introduced the first speaker and called her upon the stage to deliver her talk. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gurmanbhatia?lang=en"&gt;Gurma Bhatia&lt;/a&gt;, a Journalist, was our first speaker, and the title of her talk made me think ‘how the hell can you do that’ but she wiped out my doubts as she started talking. Title of the talk was ‘How to tell stories with code.’ &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Gurman is a journalist but she knows quite a bit about telling stories through code. Basically the talk was about how to convert data, which is difficult to comprehend, into more understandable visuals. She showed that visuals can make it easy to understand data by giving examples like Dowry deaths in Delhi, Paid Twitter followers, Decline of female singers in Bollywood music, etc. etc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Gurman, the process of telling stories through code can be broken down into three parts: 1. Collecting information; 2. Making sense of it (analyse); 3. Communicating the information. Here these steps are looking like cakewalk, but actually the story is different. However, if you want know more about it, I suggest you go ahead and check out her &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Hy_PwXLG0xXI4WYQFOZaEB9IqVsIaw8M/view"&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;, and do make sure you click on the links. Otherwise you’ll miss interesting stuff. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next talk was by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sidagarwal04"&gt;Sidhant Agarwal&lt;/a&gt; on connecting IOT with AI. Exciting, isn’t it? Rajat introduced him and handed over the stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sidhant started his &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1DLFUMEGIxqdlpya3JtelN4RmRidjJabW9taWhZSzhQMlg0/view"&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt; with explaining what is data science and from there lead it towards Artificial Intelligence. With examples he explained how a software can learn to recognize patterns if we expose it to enough relevant data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he was through half of the talk, he turned the talk towards Internet of Things and explained what it is and what impact it can have. Once we collected all parts of the puzzle, it was time to put them together. Sidhant showed how one can connect them, Artificial Intelligence and Internet of Things, efficiently with Intel hardware - Intel NUC Gateway. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It really creates an impact on the audience when speaker gives a demonstration to support his/her point. And Sidhant did the same. He connected an Intel NUC Gateway to his PC and showed that how it can detect smiling human faces and send data back for further analysis. I’m not able to fathom how much impact this technology can have on the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the talks were not only enlightening, they were mentally taxing also. So everybody wanted a snack break in order to give their minds some rest. Srijan Technologies had us covered there as well. They arranged Dominoz Pizzas with a cold drink for everybody. And of course, networking was there. I was a bit more inclined towards my Pizza, rather than networking. But guess what, I wasn’t alone who had that inclination towards pizza:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="PyDelhi Meetup" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/pydelhi-31-03-18-2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After eating pizzas, one should have a nap session. But hey! it’s PyDelhi, so it was lightning sessions’ turn. We had some young boys in the lightning sessions this time. The talks were on packaging, on documentation and Cook (which is an automated bidding system that &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hellozee54?lang=en"&gt;Kuntal&lt;/a&gt; made all by himself.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, as always, we had pitching and hiring session. In case you are looking for a job, internship or looking to hire someone for some job. So in case you are looking for a job or to hire someone, you might want to come and check this next time at the next meetup, may be you'll find what you are looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that was all for the day. I hope you enjoyed it and we will see you in the next meetup. Until then, PyDelhi signing off. Good bye.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>International Women's Day Mega Meetup</title><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/pydelhi-meetup-11-March-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-11T12:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-11T12:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anubhav Bhambri</name></author><id>tag:pydelhi.org,2018-03-11:blog/pydelhi-meetup-11-March-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I did a Google search for ‘international women’s day,’ these lines were amongst the top results of that search:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“About International Women's Day (8 March) International Women's Day (March 8) is a global day celebrating the social, economic, cultural and political achievements of women. The day also marks a call to action for accelerating gender parity.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was reading this, I was trying to find the word ‘technology,’ or something of that sort. I couldn’t find anything, maybe they didn’t think about it. I don’t know. But I know people who did think about it. PyDelhi, with other tech enthusiast communities, came together and organized a mega-meetup on 11th March, 2018, the theme of which was International Women’s Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="PyDelhi Meetup" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/pydelhi-11-03-11.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The place for the meetup was the hall at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/adobeindia?lang=en"&gt;Adobe’s&lt;/a&gt; Noida Building. A giant structure decorated with bold colors all around it with the dominance of dark grey in the middle. It looked like a great place for a mega-meetup like this one. Not only venue, Adobe also provided us with great food. Not once, thrice. And Guarav, the guy from Adobe, was really helpful and supportive. Thank Adobe!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this meetup, there were three major talks. Curious case of JAVASCRIPT BY &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hellonehha"&gt;Neha Sharma&lt;/a&gt; was the first in line. The talk was about Javascript, as you must have guessed. She explained some nice points related to Javascript. In order to have a taste of the talk, check this out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1&amp;lt;2&amp;lt;3 is true, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3&amp;gt;2&amp;gt;1 is not true. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t think that there’s something wrong with your math, it’s the Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second in line was &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tannuagarwal"&gt;Tannu Bansal&lt;/a&gt; on Amazon DynamoDB. She made a pressing point of why DynamoDB is a better choice over other options and explained ways of keeping the cost down. This session was not all theoretical, Tannu logged into her AWS account and gave some practical demonstration to the audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it was a quite informative session, yet I think the best part was when she offered that if any women who have left the industry for some reason and wants to join it again, she can contact Tannu for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third talk was ‘Infusing AI into your apps’ by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/infinitydlimit"&gt;Ruhani Arora&lt;/a&gt; from Microsoft. We all know how popular and powerful this topic is. From explaining the concepts to discussing the wide range of uses of AI, all was covered in the talk. Along with that, she covered that how Azure can play a vital role in achieving the desired results. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you must have noticed that all the speakers above were women. Even in the audience men were outnumbered by women with a big margin. Not only that, somewhat same was the case with lightning talks also. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks was the next session. The chance for everyone to let others know what he/she have got. As you all know, in lightening session, people from the audience are given five minutes to talk and present whatever idea they have. Wearable electronics, an app to pass on academic resources, natural language processing, android development for small businesses, amongst others were some topics presented by people from the audience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this meetup was to encourage women in the tech world. So is the purpose of this blog post. But when I completed the draft of this post and sent it over to a friend for proofreading, he pointed out a flaw in the post which I didn’t know how to correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He pointed out that the content of the post is well on its purpose, yet it might work the other way than expected. If women got encouraged and increased their participation, this will, in turn, encourage even more men and disbalance the sex ratio again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although he has a point, but we can’t correct it. Nobody can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jokes apart, we sincerely want and hope for more and more women participation in our meetups and the whole tech world. 
With that, we have come to the end of another meetup. But before we sign off, let me tell you which were those communities, other than PyDelhi, because of whom this all could become possible:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WWCode_Delhi"&gt;Women Who Code&lt;/a&gt;,
 &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wtm_delhi"&gt;Women Techmakers&lt;/a&gt;,
 &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/linuxchixin"&gt;LinuxChix India&lt;/a&gt;,
 &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/womenwhogo_del"&gt;Women Who Go&lt;/a&gt;,
 &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/pyladiesdelhi"&gt;PyLadies Delhi&lt;/a&gt;,
 &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mozilladelhioc"&gt;Mozilla Delhi Open Community&lt;/a&gt;,
 &lt;a href=""&gt;Women in machine learning and data science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was nice working in collaboration with all these groups. PyDelhi wants to thank them for coming together for this meetup and look forward to working with them again in future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok then. See you at the next meetup. Till next time. Happy International Women’s Day.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>PyDelhi Meetup – 17th February, 2018</title><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/pydelhi-meetup-17-February-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-17T12:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-02-17T12:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anubhav Bhambri</name></author><id>tag:pydelhi.org,2017-02-17:blog/pydelhi-meetup-17-February-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Okay! So, let me start with a question to you all. Do you think that you know python? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have been working with python for some time, then your answer to the question would probably be yes. Just like many of those who were asked “what would be the output of this:”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  def append_to(element, to=[]):
       to.append(element)
       return to

  my_list = append_to(12)
  print my_list
  my_other_list = append_to(42)
  print my_other_list
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Root3d"&gt;Gaurav&lt;/a&gt; gave a talk at the PyDelhi meetup on 17th of February, 2018. The above question is from one of the slides that he showed to everybody at the meetup. He also revealed the right answer, of course. But before I tell you what it is, let me tell you how it all started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="PyDelhi Meetup" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/pydelhi-17-02-2018.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PyDelhi meetup was held at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Fueled"&gt;Fueled&lt;/a&gt; and it started at 12 in the noon. It began with everybody giving a brief introduction about their selves. And the introduction session made it clear that people there, were from very diverse backgrounds. Yet they all had one common reason to come together – python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After introduction session completed, the talk by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Root3d"&gt;Gaurav&lt;/a&gt; on “Gotchas in python” was next. As you must have guessed, the talk was about sharing some insights of python language. But instead of simply sharing them with everyone, the speaker decided to do it the hard way (hard for us, not him). Everybody was shown some code in python and asked this question “what would be the output of this,” the same way you’ve been asked. So that everybody can test their python skills before speaker reveals the right answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have tested your python skills with the above question sincerely, then you must be thinking – ‘did the speaker at the meetup also made you wait so long for the right answer.’ So, before you start thinking that loudly, I should share the right answer with you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; [12]
 [12, 42]
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;A new list gets created once when the function is defined, and the same list is used in each successive call. But here’s what you might have expected to be the output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; [12]
 [42]
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If you got the answer right on your own, that’s great. If not, that’s even better, because it means that I’m not alone here. However, if you are thinking how this can be the output, let’s make it clear for you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python’s default arguments are evaluated once when the function is defined, not each time the function is called (like it is in say, Ruby). This means that if you use a mutable default argument and mutate it, you have mutated that object for all future calls to the function as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next session lined up after Gotchas was “Lightening Session.” In lightening session, anybody from the audience can come on the stage and give a talk in a bolt of five minutes about any topic he or she likes. If five minutes seems too short to you, I tell you what, it’s not. At PyDelhi, a lot can happen over a bolt of five minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downloading language specific software packages, machine learning, contributing to open source projects were some of the topics that people talked about in this meetup. All these talks were short, precise and to the point. PyDelhi appreciates the willingness of all these participants. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Near the end was pitching session. Anybody who’s looking for a job, want to hire someone, want a mentor, want to work on a project, etc. etc. can just simply come on the stage and let everybody know about it. If there’s somebody who’s interested in any participants pitch, can contact him or her directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pitching was the last session of the meetup. Thus, after the pitching session and with some positive feedback from the participants, one more PyDelhi meetup got concluded successfully. With the conclusion of one, a preparation for the next meetup has already started, and I hope to see you all there. Till then!.....hey! wait wait wait!!! Let me end it where we just started – do you think you know python? Let’s find out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; def create_multipliers():
     return [lambda x : i * x for i in range(5)]

 for multiplier in create_multipliers():
     print multiplier(2)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary></entry></feed>