<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyDelhi Blog</title><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/feeds/general.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pydelhi.org/blog/</id><updated>2018-11-10T11:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>PyDelhi+ILUG-D meetup at Broctagon solutions Noida</title><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/pydelhi-meetup-10-november-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-10T11:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-11-10T11:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Dheeraj jha</name></author><id>tag:pydelhi.org,2018-11-10:blog/pydelhi-meetup-10-november-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Broctagon" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/10-nov-coala-group-pyDelhi-meetup-noida.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Devsprints with coala&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At today’s dev sprint the newcomers not only learned about the open source community like Coala but also got the hands-on on to how to start contributing to open source. The talk was taken over by Kilari Teja, a software developer at Viper development and a GSoC’18 intern at Coala.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today’s talk about contributing to open source, we came across the topic of code linting which is referred to tools that analyses code to flag programming error and that's how we came across Coala.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coala is a free and open-source language-independent analysis toolkit, written in Python. Coala basically checks for the errors in the code and corrects most of them automatically and flag the others which it cannot for manual correction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started on Coala by setting up the virtualenv in our machines and then with the help of Teja and the Coala guide we were able to install and run Coala on our systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learned step by step how to run coala and check for errors and auto correct them.
Created a custom Coala file to make it run across a project of our own as a task given by the mentor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started with an introduction to the community and how it works, the mentors didn't break a sweat as the whole session went on for 4 hours including giving hands-on on the code base and solving the sample issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My Experience with ILUG-D on Debian package creation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debian is open source, totally distributed developed, community-based distribution of Linux OS and being part of this community is one of the goosebump feeling one could have. Here I am putting how I went from a normal Debian user to go ahead with the first step into its development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Debian package creation devsprints" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/10-nov-2018-pydelhi-ilug-d-debian-group.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was my first PyDelhi meetup cum dev sprints and I was totally clueless while entering at the venue. But I had experience of support from my Pycon India where 100s of developers and volunteers made me feel awesome as it was quite welcoming to be with them. I have hope for the same today as well and it went out more than my expectation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started with introduction round, we all had quite friendly and light mood hi hello with each other and since most attendees were students and that too working on any current and trending technology, I felt great already seeing all of them here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We collected our tasks on various topics ranging from coala, to open source collaboration to creating Debian package on Linux. Since Linux is love for me, I, of course, choose to go for Debian package creation group and we got introduced to Rajudev. Rajudev was our mentor for the session and he came out quite great on it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What I have covered&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker, one of most awaited tech which I was desperate to start, got sudden chance to just use it on my mac to create a Debian distribution for package creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manas, a college guy and one of Active volunteer helped me understanding docker setup while preparing our system for the task. On each step, everyone could feel free to ask from a mentor and we keep going on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We choose 2-3 different package which we had to pack for Debian, I did for pretty-ms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Debian package creation flow" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/process-of-package-creation-debian.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we went for everything, from setting up our Debian OS to installing all packager and installer, git, and pretty much everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Debian package creation" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/devsprints-debian-packaging-glimps.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While our mentor was continuously on us for each small and big questions, I felt like wow moment when I could finally see my deb file created after I had done with all commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could not finish pushing package on apt thing due to most of the time went in discussion and problem hunting of everyone while creating the package, but I felt session as too satisfying and quite great to boost morale for further development into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had some fruitful community discussion and further planning on it as we approached evening time.
I manage to get out of the box and mixed up with some blockchain and ML developers and put all my questions and had the satisfying discussion with them, and now the time came for the group pic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="pydelhi-ilug-d-group-pic" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/pydelhi-10-nov-2018-group-picture.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended with cheers on the face and some feeling of contribution for software community which we are consuming almost every time.
Till the next time, happy coding.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>PyDelhi meetup at FUELED NOIDA</title><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/pydelhi-meetup-29-september-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-29T11:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-09-29T11:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Srihari Unnikrishnan</name></author><id>tag:pydelhi.org,2018-09-29:blog/pydelhi-meetup-29-september-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="fueled" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/pydelhi-17-02-2018.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the machine learning themed pydelhi meetup kicked off with Vishal (https://github.com/vishalsangwan) giving a talk on OpenCV and facial recognition. 
Vishal started off with first clearing some basics about video and image capturing where he talked about how a computer handles video input. He uses OpenCV to take in video input using his laptop camera. Afterwards he uses facial recognition datasets to track faces in his video input using his Rasberry pi and tried out different datasets.
&lt;img alt="talk-1" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/29-09-2019-first-talk.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there was a quick lightning talk given by Raju.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we broke for snacks and networking involving a very intense foosball competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Second Talk was given by Praneet Nigam(https://github.com/Praneet460) following on the Machine Learning Train by giving a talk on Matplotlib, Seaborn and Pandas where he showcased some ways to data filtering and classification. Praneet Used a Pokemon dataset where he evaluated features of his pokemon dataset which included the height, weight and type of pokemeon. all required data for the talk can be found here.(https://github.com/Praneet460/DataVisualizationPyDelhi).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended our machine learning themed meetup with community mixer and hiring pitches. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time,
Au revoir &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>A skeptic to a believer</title><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/pydelhi-first-visit-e2enetworks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-01T12:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-09-01T12:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Rohan Sharma</name></author><id>tag:pydelhi.org,2018-09-01:blog/pydelhi-first-visit-e2enetworks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Meeting location was E2E Networks office&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a saturday and it's raining. When the whole city is drowning, i am scaling the seas to reach pyDelhi at my own office. Yes, i am an employee at E2E Networks and i was recommended to attend pyDelhi by a senior at the company who is also an active member of the pyDelhi community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a young lone wolf passionate about software development, i could never register the idea of random people meeting with a common love - Python. Never the less, i did make it to the event. I see that the space is already packed with people with eyes glimmering. Glimmering with a sense of pride to be associated with the collective enthusiasm towards building something awesome using Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I occupy a backseat, waiting for the first talk. A few minutes and some introductions down the line, it starts. It's a talk on Django Rest Framework and how to do CRUD APIs in 20 mins. An honest tech me is not thrilled being an active django developer but then i realise that it is being delivered by a college student. It slowly sinks in that even the audience has many college students. Fair enough, says the skeptic me, this event sure is beneficial to college students. Now the professional me is questioning the utility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after, my senior delivers an awesome talk on django on day 500. It is not technical detail but philosophy regarding end delivery when both application and the team size grow. It captures me. I want to shout out that i relate but i hold. As the talk concludes, professional me feels content. The thought provoking nature of the talk has enriched me somehow. A skeptic is not so skeptic anymore. But am i owned?, certainly not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's time for flash talks. Well what? Anybody can come up and speak about anything for 10 mins. That's strangely empowering. I do question the volunteers again, anything at all you say? The reply is a yes. So i commit to delivering one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talk is to follow after another talk on how to contribute to open source. It is a good talk and an anxious me has listened to it quite thoroughly. Anxious, because the talk i propose is something that is close to my heart. It is my startup idea that i had pursued quite passionately for 2 years of my college life. As my thoughts about contributing to open source and my own talk muddle together, it is already time for me to take the podium. I don't even realise that another talk has taken place which is about the success stories of python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I connect the HDMI and i put up the pitch deck on the 55 inch display. As soon as i see it, i am lost in nostalagia. I deliver the same pitch i had through and through to an audience who is looking hopeful to hear something enriching. Questions are raised, answers are given and it concludes in an applaud from everyone in the room. To get a platform to share my journey is enchanting. The skeptic me is melting at this point. The believer has arisen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pyDelhi is not only a platform for a display of tech interests but a platform that empowers you. It provides you a platform to meet like-minded people, find a job or find people to hire. Maybe you'll find a startup idea or a founder to kickstart your own. But you will most certainly find belief in how community can enrich you. So, my fellow reader, i hope to see you at the next.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>How PyDelhi conducts Hiring and Pitching sessions</title><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/pydelhi-hiring-pitching-sessions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-02T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-05-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>realslimshanky</name></author><id>tag:pydelhi.org,2018-05-02:blog/pydelhi-hiring-pitching-sessions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Hiring Pitching Sessions" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/hiringpitching.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiring and Pitching sessions have been a part of PyDelhi events since the beginning. The session is scheduled close to the end of every event just before the closing notes. This blog is to help out volunteers and participants by putting organized structure to the entire process. Points raised below are the work of volunteers, open to discussion and will be shaped better with time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Step 1 - Broadcasting on social media&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the event starts, volunteers should share a link on etherpad to note down the details of the speakers. This will help attendees to be prepared beforehand and can be called by the volunteers during the session. Also, this will be beneficial for the folks who are not able to attend the event. Official PyDelhi channels (Twitter/FB) should be preferred to broadcast the link. Etherpad link which can be used is https://public.etherpad-mozilla.org/p/Oms9Iw8MK4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Step 2 - Conducting Session&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close to the end of the event or by the schedule for Hiring and Pitching session, volunteers should open the etherpad link, preferably with the projector connected and invite the attendees to make their pitch one by one. If the person is not present, their details should be called out by volunteer themselves. After when the pre-submitted details are over, one of the volunteers should call folks from the audience to see if some of them would want to make a pitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Step 3 - Posting on Mailing Lists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the event is over, one of the volunteers should draft a mail with the details of Hiring and Pitching etherpad. Etherpad can also be used to draft the mail and can also be shared on &lt;a href="https://t.me/PyDelhigroup"&gt;PyDelhi Telegram group of Volunteers&lt;/a&gt; for one final review. After the review, mail should be posted on &lt;a href="https://mail.python.org/mailman/listinfo/ncr-python.in"&gt;PyDelhi mailing list&lt;/a&gt; and other mailing lists of FOSS user groups in and around Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence, we conclude one of the important sessions of PyDelhi.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Hello PyDelhi</title><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/hello-pydelhi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-01-17T12:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2016-01-17T12:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Saurabh Kumar</name></author><id>tag:pydelhi.org,2016-01-17:blog/hello-pydelhi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Think open-source" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/hello-world.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an example blog post. Not much here but that's not the point :)&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>