<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PyDelhi Blog</title><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/feeds/meetup.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pydelhi.org/blog/</id><updated>2018-07-10T00:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>PyDelhi Meetup at Microsoft, Gurugram</title><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/pydelhi-meetup-08-july-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-10T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-07-10T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>realslimshanky</name></author><id>tag:pydelhi.org,2018-07-10:blog/pydelhi-meetup-08-july-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Introductions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Introductions" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/8-july-2018-introductions.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time of Introductions, the hall was almost full with around 100 attendees ready to share a word about them with everyone. &lt;a href="https://www.rajatsaini.com/"&gt;Rajat&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/Gouravchawla"&gt;Gourav&lt;/a&gt; passed the mic around the hall till everyone finished their introductions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Vim or Sublime or PyCharm. Battle of the IDE's&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Panel Discussions" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/8-july-2018-panel-discussions.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great way to begin the meetup was allow folks to join a debate on which IDE was better or is it the simplicity of a text editor with few plugins which make all the difference. &lt;a href="https://github.com/akshayaurora"&gt;Akshay&lt;/a&gt; invited the panel to the stage and also folks from the audience who ever wanted to share their experience or brag about their favorite tool of trade. It almost felt like a Messi vs Ronaldo situation where folks with 5, 10+ years experience embrasing their professional IDE like PyCharm. On the other hand, those of new age like to experiment with light and memory friendly tools like Sublime. The conclusion of such a conversation cannot be obtained which can be accepted by everyone as likability of a tool is a relative. What ever rows your boat, right!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lunch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/8-july-2018-lunch.jpg"&gt;Lunching Scenes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Microsoft we had lunch and a cool place to network while during the break before the talk sessions took place. It's always great to catchup with peers and meet new folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Becoming a multilingual superhero in Django&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Sanyam Khurana" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/8-july-2018-sanyam-khurana.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://sanyamkhurana.com/"&gt;Sanyam Khurana&lt;/a&gt; proposed this talk for PyCon India 2018 and as a process of getting valuable feedback decided to deliver the same during PyDelhi. The talk is a culmation of his experiences while trying to make Django aware of different languages and adaptive to user's language preference. This idea helps localization of web applications to support various languages with help of Django. He began with explaining the prerequisites and important configuration changes in Django. Then he explained what are the different ways in which a second language can be supported like dynamic/static content. Moving on, he explained how he managed to modify templates and models and finally save the translations in static file and deliver when needed after compilation. Interesting parts of his talk was when he shared 'Gochas' which were tricky situations while in development he solved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon India 2018 Proposal - &lt;a href="https://in.pycon.org/cfp/2018/proposals/becoming-a-multilingual-superhero-in-django~bkMve/"&gt;Becoming a multilingual superhero in Django&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Keeping your Dotfiles in check with Python by Vipul Gupta&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Vipul Gupta" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/8-july-2018-vipul-gupta.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mixstersite.wordpress.com/"&gt;Vipul Gupta&lt;/a&gt; also proposed talk for PyCon India 2018 and was ready with his talk to share his experience with Dotfiles. He bagan by explaining what exactly Dotfiles are and why do a developer needs to be concerned about it especially in a *nix machine. Then came the part where he made everyone realised that there Dotfiles have been sitting in the machine all along and managed by the os but since they are human readable, becomes an advantage in development process. He explained symlinking the Dotfiles to a central directory which can be made a git repository for version control. This way even when the machine crashed or there's an os update, developer will never loose their favorite configuration. He then elaborated with how Python came in play in order to manage these Dotfiles with the help of Homely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon India 2018 Proposal - &lt;a href="https://in.pycon.org/cfp/2018/proposals/keeping-your-dotfiles-in-check-with-python~dw7Xd/"&gt;Keeping your Dotfiles in check with Python by Vipul Gupta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lightning Talk and Hiring/Pitching Session&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Manas Kashyap" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/8-july-2018-manas-kashyap.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://qa.debian.org/developer.php?email=manaskashyaptech%40gmail.com"&gt;Manas Kashyap&lt;/a&gt; gave a lightning talk about 'Python Packaging- The messy wormhole'. He has been packaging node modules for Debian lately and explained the process Debian uses in a brief time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/debpackaging"&gt;Packaging Doc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Gaurav Sehrawat" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/8-july-2018-gaurav-sherawat.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/igauravsehrawat"&gt;Gaurav Sehrawat&lt;/a&gt; gave a talk explaining different DNS records a person can use while managing hosting account. He used his clean and self explanatory slides for the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides - &lt;a href="http://igauravsehrawat.com/MyTalks/PyDelhi/dns-records/DNS%20Name%20Records.slides.html#/"&gt;DNS Records&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Community Mixer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Manas representing ILUGD" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/8-july-2018-manas-represents-ilugd.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a part where we invite different open source communities around Delhi to pitch their work and invite volunteer and collaboraters. For this meetup we had &lt;a href="http://india.linuxchix.org"&gt;LinuxChix India&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/Pyladies-Delhi"&gt;PyLadies Delhi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.linuxdelhi.org"&gt;Indian Linux User Groups Delhi&lt;/a&gt; 's volunteer who explained what they are working on and how to attend their next meetup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the event it was time to pitch &lt;a href="https://in.pycon.org"&gt;PyCon India 2018&lt;/a&gt; which is scheduled for early October and invite folks who are willing to volunteer for the same. Also, &lt;a href="https://pydelhi.org"&gt;PyDelhi&lt;/a&gt; which is responsible for the meetup in progress shared more about the community and how a person can volunteer to make these events happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you follow us on our social media accounts to get news about the next event. Checkout &lt;a href="https://pydelhi.org"&gt;PyDelhi.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>PyDelhi Devsprint at Knowlarity, Gurugram</title><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/pydelhi-meetup-28-april-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-28T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-04-28T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Aaqa Ishtyaq</name></author><id>tag:pydelhi.org,2018-04-28:blog/pydelhi-meetup-28-april-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meetup at Knowlarity" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/pydelhi-28-04-18-1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time the meetup was at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/knowlarity"&gt;Knowlarity&lt;/a&gt;, Ambience Mall, Gurugram. It began with everybody giving a brief introduction about their selves. And &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ErSanyamKhurana"&gt;Sanyam&lt;/a&gt; started the introductory session of what is a Dev sprint? During Dev sprint, Mentors/Contributors of Open source projects guides participants from generating development build to submit a patch for a bug. It is best opportunity to experience the culture of Open source contribution. People from newbie to experienced together contribute to project. During the session, if you are stuck you can solve your confusions instantly by discussing with mentors. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ambarishKnow"&gt;Ambarish Gupta&lt;/a&gt;, CEO Knowlarity, also introduced himself and the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The organisations who participated in this dev sprints along with their mentors were  :
1. &lt;a href="https://kivy.org"&gt;Kivy&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="https://github.com/akshayaurora"&gt;Akshay Arora&lt;/a&gt;
2. &lt;a href="https://coala.io"&gt;Coala&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="https://github.com/hemangsk"&gt;Hemang Kumar&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/rj722"&gt;Rahul Jha&lt;/a&gt;
3. &lt;a href="https://mozilla.org"&gt;Mozilla&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="https://github.com/curiouslearner"&gt;Sanyam Khurana&lt;/a&gt; for AddOn Server, Remo and Mozilla Central and &lt;a href="https://github.com/realslimshanky"&gt;Shashank Kumar&lt;/a&gt; for AddOn Frontend
4. &lt;a href="https://python.org"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="https://github.com/curiouslearner"&gt;Sanyam Khurana&lt;/a&gt; for CPython &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the introductory session, everyone chose their project in which they wanted to contribute and the dev sprint started. But there were a bunch of students who were unfamiliar with Git and Github, so &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/priyankt68"&gt;Priyank&lt;/a&gt; took the initiative to teach git/github to those students. 
The environment was full of zeal. Half way through the devsprint it was lunch time and Knowlarity had very generously sponsored lunch for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Devsprint at knowlarity" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/pydelhi-28-04-18-2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after lunch, everyone was back to their work. Before hiring and pitching session, there was an inspirational talk by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ajayshr"&gt;Ajay Shrivastava&lt;/a&gt;, CTO Knowlarity, with a closing remark &lt;em&gt;"Work smart AND work hard. There is never a choice between the two. After all, it took Messi 17 years and 114 days to become an overnight success!"&lt;/em&gt;. After his talk was hiring and pitching session. Anybody who’s looking for a job, want to hire someone, want a mentor, want to work on a project, etc. can just simply come on and let everybody know about it. If there’s somebody who’s interested in any participants pitch, can contact them directly.
So that was all for the day. Devsprint concluded with 11 Issues, 5 Pull requests and lots of swag from Pydelhi and Github successfully. I hope you have enjoyed it and would join us at the &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/pydelhi/"&gt;next meetup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>PyDelhi Meetup at Connaught Place</title><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/pydelhi-meetup-31-march-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-31T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-31T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anubhav Bhambri</name></author><id>tag:pydelhi.org,2018-03-31:blog/pydelhi-meetup-31-march-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="PyDelhi Meetup" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/pydelhi-31-03-18-1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time the meetup was at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Srijan"&gt;Srijan Technologies&lt;/a&gt;, Connaught Place, Delhi. And everybody was already half way through the introduction session when I reached (yeah, I was late). Everybody introduced themselves and we straight away jumped into the talks without any further ado.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rajataaron"&gt;Rajat&lt;/a&gt; introduced the first speaker and called her upon the stage to deliver her talk. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gurmanbhatia?lang=en"&gt;Gurma Bhatia&lt;/a&gt;, a Journalist, was our first speaker, and the title of her talk made me think ‘how the hell can you do that’ but she wiped out my doubts as she started talking. Title of the talk was ‘How to tell stories with code.’ &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Gurman is a journalist but she knows quite a bit about telling stories through code. Basically the talk was about how to convert data, which is difficult to comprehend, into more understandable visuals. She showed that visuals can make it easy to understand data by giving examples like Dowry deaths in Delhi, Paid Twitter followers, Decline of female singers in Bollywood music, etc. etc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Gurman, the process of telling stories through code can be broken down into three parts: 1. Collecting information; 2. Making sense of it (analyse); 3. Communicating the information. Here these steps are looking like cakewalk, but actually the story is different. However, if you want know more about it, I suggest you go ahead and check out her &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Hy_PwXLG0xXI4WYQFOZaEB9IqVsIaw8M/view"&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;, and do make sure you click on the links. Otherwise you’ll miss interesting stuff. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next talk was by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sidagarwal04"&gt;Sidhant Agarwal&lt;/a&gt; on connecting IOT with AI. Exciting, isn’t it? Rajat introduced him and handed over the stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sidhant started his &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1DLFUMEGIxqdlpya3JtelN4RmRidjJabW9taWhZSzhQMlg0/view"&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt; with explaining what is data science and from there lead it towards Artificial Intelligence. With examples he explained how a software can learn to recognize patterns if we expose it to enough relevant data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he was through half of the talk, he turned the talk towards Internet of Things and explained what it is and what impact it can have. Once we collected all parts of the puzzle, it was time to put them together. Sidhant showed how one can connect them, Artificial Intelligence and Internet of Things, efficiently with Intel hardware - Intel NUC Gateway. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It really creates an impact on the audience when speaker gives a demonstration to support his/her point. And Sidhant did the same. He connected an Intel NUC Gateway to his PC and showed that how it can detect smiling human faces and send data back for further analysis. I’m not able to fathom how much impact this technology can have on the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the talks were not only enlightening, they were mentally taxing also. So everybody wanted a snack break in order to give their minds some rest. Srijan Technologies had us covered there as well. They arranged Dominoz Pizzas with a cold drink for everybody. And of course, networking was there. I was a bit more inclined towards my Pizza, rather than networking. But guess what, I wasn’t alone who had that inclination towards pizza:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="PyDelhi Meetup" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/pydelhi-31-03-18-2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After eating pizzas, one should have a nap session. But hey! it’s PyDelhi, so it was lightning sessions’ turn. We had some young boys in the lightning sessions this time. The talks were on packaging, on documentation and Cook (which is an automated bidding system that &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hellozee54?lang=en"&gt;Kuntal&lt;/a&gt; made all by himself.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, as always, we had pitching and hiring session. In case you are looking for a job, internship or looking to hire someone for some job. So in case you are looking for a job or to hire someone, you might want to come and check this next time at the next meetup, may be you'll find what you are looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that was all for the day. I hope you enjoyed it and we will see you in the next meetup. Until then, PyDelhi signing off. Good bye.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>International Women's Day Mega Meetup</title><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/pydelhi-meetup-11-March-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-11T12:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-11T12:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anubhav Bhambri</name></author><id>tag:pydelhi.org,2018-03-11:blog/pydelhi-meetup-11-March-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I did a Google search for ‘international women’s day,’ these lines were amongst the top results of that search:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“About International Women's Day (8 March) International Women's Day (March 8) is a global day celebrating the social, economic, cultural and political achievements of women. The day also marks a call to action for accelerating gender parity.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was reading this, I was trying to find the word ‘technology,’ or something of that sort. I couldn’t find anything, maybe they didn’t think about it. I don’t know. But I know people who did think about it. PyDelhi, with other tech enthusiast communities, came together and organized a mega-meetup on 11th March, 2018, the theme of which was International Women’s Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="PyDelhi Meetup" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/pydelhi-11-03-11.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The place for the meetup was the hall at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/adobeindia?lang=en"&gt;Adobe’s&lt;/a&gt; Noida Building. A giant structure decorated with bold colors all around it with the dominance of dark grey in the middle. It looked like a great place for a mega-meetup like this one. Not only venue, Adobe also provided us with great food. Not once, thrice. And Guarav, the guy from Adobe, was really helpful and supportive. Thank Adobe!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this meetup, there were three major talks. Curious case of JAVASCRIPT BY &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hellonehha"&gt;Neha Sharma&lt;/a&gt; was the first in line. The talk was about Javascript, as you must have guessed. She explained some nice points related to Javascript. In order to have a taste of the talk, check this out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1&amp;lt;2&amp;lt;3 is true, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3&amp;gt;2&amp;gt;1 is not true. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t think that there’s something wrong with your math, it’s the Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second in line was &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tannuagarwal"&gt;Tannu Bansal&lt;/a&gt; on Amazon DynamoDB. She made a pressing point of why DynamoDB is a better choice over other options and explained ways of keeping the cost down. This session was not all theoretical, Tannu logged into her AWS account and gave some practical demonstration to the audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it was a quite informative session, yet I think the best part was when she offered that if any women who have left the industry for some reason and wants to join it again, she can contact Tannu for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third talk was ‘Infusing AI into your apps’ by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/infinitydlimit"&gt;Ruhani Arora&lt;/a&gt; from Microsoft. We all know how popular and powerful this topic is. From explaining the concepts to discussing the wide range of uses of AI, all was covered in the talk. Along with that, she covered that how Azure can play a vital role in achieving the desired results. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you must have noticed that all the speakers above were women. Even in the audience men were outnumbered by women with a big margin. Not only that, somewhat same was the case with lightning talks also. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks was the next session. The chance for everyone to let others know what he/she have got. As you all know, in lightening session, people from the audience are given five minutes to talk and present whatever idea they have. Wearable electronics, an app to pass on academic resources, natural language processing, android development for small businesses, amongst others were some topics presented by people from the audience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this meetup was to encourage women in the tech world. So is the purpose of this blog post. But when I completed the draft of this post and sent it over to a friend for proofreading, he pointed out a flaw in the post which I didn’t know how to correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He pointed out that the content of the post is well on its purpose, yet it might work the other way than expected. If women got encouraged and increased their participation, this will, in turn, encourage even more men and disbalance the sex ratio again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although he has a point, but we can’t correct it. Nobody can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jokes apart, we sincerely want and hope for more and more women participation in our meetups and the whole tech world. 
With that, we have come to the end of another meetup. But before we sign off, let me tell you which were those communities, other than PyDelhi, because of whom this all could become possible:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WWCode_Delhi"&gt;Women Who Code&lt;/a&gt;,
 &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wtm_delhi"&gt;Women Techmakers&lt;/a&gt;,
 &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/linuxchixin"&gt;LinuxChix India&lt;/a&gt;,
 &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/womenwhogo_del"&gt;Women Who Go&lt;/a&gt;,
 &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/pyladiesdelhi"&gt;PyLadies Delhi&lt;/a&gt;,
 &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mozilladelhioc"&gt;Mozilla Delhi Open Community&lt;/a&gt;,
 &lt;a href=""&gt;Women in machine learning and data science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was nice working in collaboration with all these groups. PyDelhi wants to thank them for coming together for this meetup and look forward to working with them again in future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok then. See you at the next meetup. Till next time. Happy International Women’s Day.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>PyDelhi Meetup – 17th March, 2018</title><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/pydelhi-meetup-17-March-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-03-17T12:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-03-17T12:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anubhav Bhambri &amp; Srihari UnniKrishnan</name></author><id>tag:pydelhi.org,2017-03-17:blog/pydelhi-meetup-17-March-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Saturday, 17/03/2018, was the day for another PyDelhi meetup. A day for tech lovers to come together and learn from each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="PyDelhi Meetup" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/pydelhi-17-3-2018.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The venue of the meetup was again &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Fueled"&gt;Fueled&lt;/a&gt;, Noida. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rajataaron"&gt;Rajat&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TechDeviant"&gt;Gourav&lt;/a&gt; came to the stage and started the meetup with the introductions. Since in every meetup there are people who are coming for the first time, it’s good to start with introductions. One by one, everybody, including the hosts and the audience, gave a brief introduction about themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the introduction session, Rajat and Gourav also shared some useful information about the PyDelhi. Like about the PyDelhi Volunteer Group on Telegram (which you can join &lt;a href="https://t.me/joinchat/AAAAAEK2nzPg0IlwbbAing"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) and the fact that PyDelhi is one of the organizers of &lt;a href="https://in.pycon.org/2018/"&gt;PyCon India 2018&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After introductions, it was time for the Talk Session and the first talk was given by &lt;a href="https://github.com/sourabhtk37"&gt;TK Saurabh&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://slides.com/tksourabh/basics-logging-in-python#/3"&gt;logging in python&lt;/a&gt;. The talk highlighted the basic features of Logging and why we should consider it over print statement debugging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He discussed various techniques and methods that are available in the python logging module in the std lib. Including implementation/demo of the sample application with logging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TK talked about the different logging levels, Loggers and LogRecords, Handlers and Formatters. He also talked about the ways to configure logging manually or by using File Config or DictConfig. The code for the above talk is pushed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was snack break after the first talk, and when everybody was done with their Samosas, we started with the second talk – Github for Noobs by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/2aniketmaithani"&gt;Aniket&lt;/a&gt;. It was a very basic tutorial on how to use version control management service through Git and Github to maintain your code. The talk explained basic features of Git. &lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt;Git and Github are two different things not to be confused with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to explain the whole thing, Aniket demonstrated how to push a simple commit into an empty repository with a few commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git init &lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git remote add origin "link to repo url...." &lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git add .&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git commit -m "init" &lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git push -u origin master &lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what each line of code is doing:
-   The first line creates an empty repository into your project directory.
-   The second line acts as a pointer for your Git directory to your repository on Github/GitLab/whatever the link to which is defined by the origin.
-   The third line stages all your changes for the commit.
-   The fourth line commits your changes into the Git file with a description "init" for initialize.
-   The last line pushes your commits or changes into your repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Gourav announced the lightning Talk Session. Amongst others, there was a lightening talk which was not related to python or anything technical for that matter. The talk was given by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bhanuvrat"&gt;Anuvrat&lt;/a&gt; on touch typing, i.e. typing with all your fingers without looking at the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="PyDelhi Meetup" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/touchtyping-17-3-2018.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk started with two-sided verbal communication between the speaker and the audience. But gradually speaker started to type, which was being projected on the screen, and stopped talking entirely. As you can see in the picture above. Speaker was communicating with the audience through typed text and showing what is it like to do touch typing. Do you think we can even call it a ‘talk’ anymore? Never mind!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the end of the talk, the speaker invited everybody for a race on typeracer.com. Anuvrat and some people in the audience joined the race. Results of the race showed that there were more people in the audience who know touch typing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, it was pitching session at the end. Where people can let everyone know about the thing that they are looking for. You can subscribe to the &lt;a href="https://mail.python.org/mailman/listinfo/ncr-python.in"&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; in case you want to check out all the pitches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was all for the day. Another PyDelhi meetup got concluded successfully. I hope you have enjoyed it and would join us at the &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/pydelhi/"&gt;next meetup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>PyDelhi Meetup – 17th February, 2018</title><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/pydelhi-meetup-17-February-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-17T12:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-02-17T12:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anubhav Bhambri</name></author><id>tag:pydelhi.org,2017-02-17:blog/pydelhi-meetup-17-February-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Okay! So, let me start with a question to you all. Do you think that you know python? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have been working with python for some time, then your answer to the question would probably be yes. Just like many of those who were asked “what would be the output of this:”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  def append_to(element, to=[]):
       to.append(element)
       return to

  my_list = append_to(12)
  print my_list
  my_other_list = append_to(42)
  print my_other_list
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Root3d"&gt;Gaurav&lt;/a&gt; gave a talk at the PyDelhi meetup on 17th of February, 2018. The above question is from one of the slides that he showed to everybody at the meetup. He also revealed the right answer, of course. But before I tell you what it is, let me tell you how it all started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="PyDelhi Meetup" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/pydelhi-17-02-2018.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PyDelhi meetup was held at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Fueled"&gt;Fueled&lt;/a&gt; and it started at 12 in the noon. It began with everybody giving a brief introduction about their selves. And the introduction session made it clear that people there, were from very diverse backgrounds. Yet they all had one common reason to come together – python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After introduction session completed, the talk by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Root3d"&gt;Gaurav&lt;/a&gt; on “Gotchas in python” was next. As you must have guessed, the talk was about sharing some insights of python language. But instead of simply sharing them with everyone, the speaker decided to do it the hard way (hard for us, not him). Everybody was shown some code in python and asked this question “what would be the output of this,” the same way you’ve been asked. So that everybody can test their python skills before speaker reveals the right answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have tested your python skills with the above question sincerely, then you must be thinking – ‘did the speaker at the meetup also made you wait so long for the right answer.’ So, before you start thinking that loudly, I should share the right answer with you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; [12]
 [12, 42]
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;A new list gets created once when the function is defined, and the same list is used in each successive call. But here’s what you might have expected to be the output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; [12]
 [42]
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If you got the answer right on your own, that’s great. If not, that’s even better, because it means that I’m not alone here. However, if you are thinking how this can be the output, let’s make it clear for you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python’s default arguments are evaluated once when the function is defined, not each time the function is called (like it is in say, Ruby). This means that if you use a mutable default argument and mutate it, you have mutated that object for all future calls to the function as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next session lined up after Gotchas was “Lightening Session.” In lightening session, anybody from the audience can come on the stage and give a talk in a bolt of five minutes about any topic he or she likes. If five minutes seems too short to you, I tell you what, it’s not. At PyDelhi, a lot can happen over a bolt of five minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downloading language specific software packages, machine learning, contributing to open source projects were some of the topics that people talked about in this meetup. All these talks were short, precise and to the point. PyDelhi appreciates the willingness of all these participants. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Near the end was pitching session. Anybody who’s looking for a job, want to hire someone, want a mentor, want to work on a project, etc. etc. can just simply come on the stage and let everybody know about it. If there’s somebody who’s interested in any participants pitch, can contact him or her directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pitching was the last session of the meetup. Thus, after the pitching session and with some positive feedback from the participants, one more PyDelhi meetup got concluded successfully. With the conclusion of one, a preparation for the next meetup has already started, and I hope to see you all there. Till then!.....hey! wait wait wait!!! Let me end it where we just started – do you think you know python? Let’s find out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; def create_multipliers():
     return [lambda x : i * x for i in range(5)]

 for multiplier in create_multipliers():
     print multiplier(2)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>PyDelhi MayPy</title><link href="https://pydelhi.org/blog/pydelhi-meetup-14-may-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-14T12:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2016-05-14T12:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Harshit Tyagi</name></author><id>tag:pydelhi.org,2016-05-14:blog/pydelhi-meetup-14-may-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;May 14th marked by scorching heat and to tackle it we had some cool Python libraries and Framework to learn, share and interact at the PyDelhi Meetup at Fueled Noida Office. Attended by 40 python enthusiasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- [![PyDelhi Meetup]()](https://twitter.com/PyDelhi/status/731416447285518336) --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="PyDelhi Meetup" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/pydelhi-14-05-16.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hackathon Listing Platform using Django Framework&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First we had Pulkit Pahwa, taking up a knowledge enriching session on &lt;a href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/1.9/"&gt;Django Web Framework&lt;/a&gt;. The agenda was to build a Hackathon listing platform sort of a mini-hackerearth which required basic knowledge of Python. Started with the creation of the Django project,and then an app for Hackathon related information with the &lt;a href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/1.9/topics/db/models/"&gt;models.py&lt;/a&gt; dealing with the data and &lt;a href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/1.9/ref/models/fields/"&gt;model fields&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;code&gt;urls.py&lt;/code&gt; for url configurations and mapping the urls to the handlers lodged in the &lt;code&gt;views.py&lt;/code&gt; of our app using the &lt;a href="https://www.fullstackpython.com/object-relational-mappers-orms.html"&gt;Django ORM&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following explains the entire flow of the web application built on Django.
&lt;img alt="PyDelhi Meetup" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/django_request_response_cycle.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interaction led process of &lt;a href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/1.9/ref/request-response/"&gt;request response cycle&lt;/a&gt; and how Django handles the requests and rendering the data onto the templates. A nicely pulled up session came to an end with our dummy Hackathon lists brightening up our pages running on our very own Django development server with developers getting in touch with the awesomeness(speed and ease) of the Django Framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refreshments are just a way to get to interact with people about their work experience, their findings, and best practices of problem solving. You never know which statement might prove helpful to you at what point in your project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="PyDelhi Meetup" src="https://pydelhi.org/blog/images/pydelhi-may-2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting Python to interact with Java and objc using PyJnius and PyObjus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we had a talk on "Getting python to interact with Java, Obj-C using PyJnius and PyObjus." by Akkshay Arora, - Python, Linux lover, core-dev of &lt;a href="http://kivy.org­"&gt;kivy&lt;/a&gt;. The discussion involved a few python libraries which provide modules and methods to interact with other languages without diving much into it. The usage of this can simply be explained by thinking of a situation where you can have the best of two languages with the knowledge of one -  feels weird right? But this is actually possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/kivy/pyjnius"&gt;PyJNIus&lt;/a&gt; - A Python module to access Java classes as Python classes using JNI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a quick overview : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;jnius&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;autoclass&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;autoclass&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;java.lang.System&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;out&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;println&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;Hello world&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;Hello&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;world&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;Stack&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;autoclass&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;java.util.Stack&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;stack&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Stack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;stack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;push&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;hello&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;stack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;push&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;world&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;stack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;pop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;world&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;stack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;pop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;hello&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now with this great library the difference to other projects is that apps can take advantage of 
&lt;a href="https://kivy.org/planet/2016/05/android-apps-with-python-flask-and-a-webview/"&gt;python-for-android’s&lt;/a&gt; relatively extensive toolchain including python3.5 support, the ability to build popular libraries like numpy, support for multiple architectures, and access to the Android API via PyJNIus or Plyer rather than SL4A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/kivy/pyobjus"&gt;PyObjus&lt;/a&gt; - Python module for accessing Objective-C classes as Python classes using Objective-C runtime reflection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;pyobjus&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;autoclass&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;objc_str&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;pyobjus.dylib_manager&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;load_framework&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;INCLUDE&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;load_framework&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;INCLUDE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;AppKit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# get nsalert class&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;NSAlert&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;autoclass&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;NSAlert&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# create an NSAlert object, and show it.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;alert&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;NSAlert&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;alloc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;init&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;alert&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;setMessageText_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;objc_str&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;Hello world!&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;alert&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;runModal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;code&gt;autoclass&lt;/code&gt; is the heart of pyobjus. With this function, you load Objective C classes into pyobjus which then constructs a Python wrapper around these objects. You can load external code into pyobjus using the &lt;code&gt;load_framework&lt;/code&gt; function, or by using &lt;code&gt;load_dylib&lt;/code&gt;. The
&lt;code&gt;load_framework&lt;/code&gt; function uses NSBundle for loading the framework into pyobjus, and the &lt;code&gt;load_dylib&lt;/code&gt; function uses &lt;code&gt;ctypes&lt;/code&gt; for loading external .&lt;code&gt;dylib&lt;/code&gt; objects into pyobjus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well this is just a trailer and here we believe the script of the movie should be written by you. Keep exploring and explain yourself the reason why these excellent libraries and frameworks have been built with a Project or application. Because Necessity is long gone. Now innovation mothers Invention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subscribe to our blog and follow us on social media and keep coming to the meetups on alternate Saturdays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to meet you!! Till then this is PyDelhi signing off.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>